Finding Aid for the Ralph J. Bunche Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Ralph J. Bunche Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0061
2.50 linear_feet
- A Brief and Tentative Analysis of Negro Leadership (September 1940), including: (Box 1, File 1)
  General Survey of Negro Leadership
  Illustrations of Negro Leadership Types
  Life Histories Analysis
  Leadership Schedules
  General but Incomplete List of Negro Leaders
  Leadership Bibliography
- 2 Conceptions and Ideologies of the Negro Problem (March 5, 1940), including: (Box 1, File 2)
  The American "Faith"
  The Nature of Ideologies
  Scope of thinking on the Negro problem
  Frame of reference, assumptions and value premises
  Analysis of thought on the Negro problem
  Negro, general
  Negro, early slavery
  Negro, slave revolt
  Free Negro, ante-bellum
  Negro, colonization and ’deportation
  Analysis of thought on the Negro Problem
  White, anti-slavery
  White, rationalization of slavery
  White, slave influence on
  White, conception of the Negro
  Possible emancipation Negro thought on the Negro problem
  General
  "Accommodation" ideologies
  "Escapist" ideologies
  Appendix I: Comments on Geographical, etc. Differentials
  Appendix II: Bryant’s analysis of ideologies revealed i n organization Questionnaires
- The Political Status of the Negro - Book 1 (September 1940), including: (Box 1, File 3)
  Introductory Remarks
  Historical Background for the Study of Negro Political Status
- The Political Status of the Negro - Book 2, Part 1 (September 1940), Including: (Box 1, File 4)
  The Southern Political Process
- The Political Status of the Negro - Book 2, Part 2 (September 1940), including: (Box 1, File 5)
  Registration Procedure i n the South
- The Political Status of the Negro - Book 2, Part 3 (September 1940), including: (Box 1, File 6)
  Negro Registration
- The Political Status of the Negro - Book 3 (September 1940), including: (Box 1, File 7)
  The Poll Tax
- The Political Status of the Negro - Book 4 (September 1940), including: (Box 1, File 8)
  The Negro at the Southern Polls
  The Democratic or "White Primaries i n the South"
- The Political Status of the Negro - Book 5 (September 1940), including: (Box 1, File 9)
  Negro Voting i n the A. A. A. Cotton Referenda
  Negroes i n Atlanta
  Memphis
  The Negro as an Issue i n Southern Politics
  Republican Politics in the South
  Southern Liberalism
- The Political Status of the Negro - Book 6 (September 1940), including: (Box 1, File 10)
  Negro Political Activity in the North
  The Negro Office-Holder i n The Federal Government
  Crisis Chart of Negro Office-Holders
  Benefits from Negro Political Activity in the South
- The Political Status of the Negro - Book 7 (September 1940), including: (Box 1, File 11)
  Appendix I: Summary of Election Laws of Eleven Southern States
  Appendix II: Elements of the Population Voting in Selected Counties
  Appendix III: Race as a Factor i n the Popular Vote of the South
  Bibliography
- The Programs, Ideologies, Tactics and Achievements of Negro Betterment and Interracial Organizations - Book 1 (June 1940), including: (Box 1, File 12)
  Prefatory Statement & Introduction
  Part I - Niagara Movement
  National Association for the Advancement of Colored People
- The Programs, Ideologies, Tactics and Achievements of Negro Betterment and Interracial Organizations - Book 2 (June 1940), including: (Box 1, File 13)
  Amenia Conference of 1916
  The National Urban League
  National Negro Business League
  Negro Cooperative Guild
  National Negro Congress
  Southern Negro Youth Congress
  The New Negro Alliance
  Marcus Garvey U.N.I.A.
- The Programs, Ideologies, Tactics and Achievements of Negro Betterment and Interracial Organizations - Book 3 (June 1940), including: (Box 1, File 14)
  Peace Movement of Ethiopia
  National Movement f o r 49th State
  Commission on Interracial Cooperation
  Interracial Activity of the Y.M.C.A.
  Commission on Race Relations of Federal Council of Churches
  Fellowship of Reconciliation
  Interracial Department of the National Council of Y.M.C.A.
- The Programs, Ideologies, Tactics and Achievements of Negro Betterment and Interracial Organizations - Book 4 (June 1940), including: (Box 1, File 15)
  Interracial Committee of the District of Columbia
  Interracial Activity of the Society of Friends
  The Catholic Interracial Council
  Critique on the Interracial Organizations
  Analysis of Questionnaires from Interracial Groups
  Independent Local Organizations
  Analysis of Questionnaires from Local Organizations
  Miscellaneous Negro Organizations
  Liberal and "Left Wing" Organizations
  Questionnaire Analysis of "Left Wing" Groups
  Civic Protest, Betterment and Propaganda Organizations of Minority" Groups other-than Negro
  Anti-Negro Organizations
  General Critique of Negro Organizations
  Constructive Suggestions